Robert Raftery

Experienced Software Developer

braftery@protonmail.com

Summary

Senior Developer with full-stack web experience implementing Internet-facing websites. Developed and maintained database-driven web apps in Java J2EE hosted on RedHat Linux, Microsoft IIS/Active Server Pages (ASP) hosted on Microsoft Server, JSP-based websites using an enterprise Content Management System (CMS), and PHP hosted on RedHat Linux.

Possess excellent communication skills both written and oral. Proficient with full software development life cycle. Experienced at object-oriented analysis and design. Self-starter that thrives in a team environment.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Union Bank

December 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 4 months)

Responsible for support of 2 vendor applications: a fraud case management application and a fraud detection application, installation of new vendor software releases, maintenance of Informatica ETL (Extract-Transform-Load) jobs, develop and maintain Oracle SQL queries for ad-hoc reporting.

Senior Support Engineer at Union Bank

April 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 9 months)

Responsible for 2nd/3rd level Production Support for 70 Internet-facing, database-driven Java J2EE web applications. Duties include incident management, triage incoming incidents, identify and coordinate with necessary technical support teams to drive to a timely resolution, investigate and gather the information necessary to handoff to the application team if appropriate, manage and document the incidents using the enterprise ticketing systems, drive reorganizing the information architecture of the departmental wiki, write/document Splunk queries to provide cross-application analysis and reporting, mentor junior team members, advise teammates on automating application validation scripting using Microsoft HTA (HTML Applications) and Java, onboard new applications for support by interviewing the application development team and documenting key support topics in the departmental wiki, represent Enterprise Application Support interests in Enterprise Change Management meetings.

Senior Developer at Union Bank

September 2007 - April 2012 (4 years 8 months)

Following is a list of Internet-facing websites owned and operated by Union Bank. The website content is maintained and published by the SDL Tridion Enterprise CMS system.

* www.unionbank.com

Responsible for designing and creating static HTML from comps and maintaining vendor-created HTML, for creating advanced Javascript scripts and maintaining vendor-supplied Javascript scripts, for designing, creating and implementing the components, component templates, page templates and other artifacts necessary to enable the Content Management Team to manage the previous list of websites and their content.

Responsible for designing, creating and implementing various reports and site management utilities implemented in ASP, ASP.NET, and Oracle SQL Views.

Responsible for rewriting the BLW application, (http://blw.unionbank.com/), an Internet-facing website responsible for displaying the nearest Bank branches, ATM's and various other services based on location information provided by the web visitor. The application is implemented in PHP and MySQL on the server-side and and uses the Google Maps API v2.0 and jQuery in the browser.

"Skinned" the output results from a Google Search Appliance using XSLT to conform to www.unionbank.com's look-n-feel and to conform to www.highmarkcapital.com's look-n-feel. Responsible for creating the Dynamic XHTML mockup for www.highmarkcapital.com. The XHTML, CSS and Javascript logic from the mockup was then used by a team of 3 other developers and myself to create the Tridion Page Templates, Component Templates, Components and other artifacts to implement the final version to be turned-over to the Content Management Team for content entry and site creation.

Contract Programmer at Union Bank

September 2006 - August 2007 (1 year)

Created and implemented a Microsoft HTML Application (HTA) consisting of HTML, Dynamic HTML, JScript and Windows Script Host, (WSH). The purpose of the HTML Application was to secure a vendor application by strictly limiting the PC operator to making choices from a menu presented by the HTA. To that end the HTA automated the operator's manual processes and "front-ended" the vendor application.

Senior Developer WRI Application at Union Bank

January 2004 - April 2005 (1 year 4 months)

WRI (Returned Items on the Web), is a customer-facing J2EE web application that notifies Bank customers when a deposited item has been returned and enables the customer to display an image of the item as well as information about the returned item. Worked on the Welcome Page using Java Servlet, JSP, Enterprise Session Bean, Enterprise Entity Beans; created

^{*} www.hoabankers.com

^{*} www.highmarkcapital.com

SQL scripts to assist with performane testing and functional testing; create SQL Views in Oracle 9i database to support automated customer notifications; performed analysis; coordinated testing and development with outside development groups; negotiated and documented functional and non-functional apsects of data feed with mainframe application. Mentored team members in using the IBM AIX to implement, monitor, and test various parts of the application. Developed Unix Shell scripts to automate repetitive tasks. Created automated build scripts using Apache Ant and Windows 2000 shell scripts.

Senior Developer PPW Application at Union Bank

January 2003 - January 2004 (1 year 1 month)

PPW (Positive Pay on the Web), is a customer-facing J2EE web application to enable customers to display information and images of the customer's positive pay items. Developed application-specific logging proxy to insulate the application from the logging implementation used. The log proxy used Jakarta Log4J. Also, created custom classes to extend the JDBC Appender for Log4J to enable fine-grained logging of specific object properties and a custom parser to support same.

Developed multi-threaded job scheduler component, in Java, for running various application-specific tasks. Used JUnit for unit testing. Assisted in creating automated build scripts using Apache Ant and Windows 2000 shell scripts.; Designed both components using UML diagrams.

Senior Developer MDCU Client at Union Bank

January 2003 - January 2003 (1 month)

MDCU (Market Driven Contact Us), Enterprise service, implemented in Java, for capturing and routing customer communications with appropriate customer support department. Developed a JavaMail component to support the application.

Senior Developer TOPS Application at Union Bank

January 1999 - January 2003 (4 years 1 month)

TOPS, is an intranet web application running on Microsoft IIS using Active Server Pages (ASP), Seagate Crystal Reports, and MS SQL 2000 database. The application automates monitoring and tracking the non-financial aspects of commercial loans and, also, covenant compliance. Developed ASP pages using server-side logic written in VBScript and JScript and extensive client-side logic written in JavaScript. Developed database views, database user-defined functions (UDF), and stored procedures in TSQL for reporting purposes. Coordinated with end users to develop business requirements and reporting specifications. Lead two other developers in the implementaion of several reports in Seagate Crystal Reports.

Senior Developer RACER Application at Union Bank

January 1997 - January 1999 (2 years 1 month)

RACER (Rapid Application, Credit Execution and Reporting), is a Lotus Notes workflow application that automates the approval and routing process for commercial loan applications and renewals.

Senior Developer Prospect Tracking at Union Bank

January 1994 - January 1997 (3 years 1 month)

Developed and maintained a "fat-client" application written in dBASE IV. The application was a date-tickler used to monitor various aspects of commercial loans. Also during this period, I converted data from the legacy applications and imported it into the new date-tickler application. Also, supported the roll-out of a new customer relationship management vendor application.

Senior Developer at Union Bank

January 1990 - January 1993 (3 years 1 month)

Maintained several applications written in RPGII running on 30 different IBM Sys/36 computers on the Bank's wide-area network. The applications communicated with the mainframe using RJE (Remote Job Entry) to upload data and JCL (Job Control Language) to run the mainframe jobs. Additionally, the applications screen-scraped CICS application using SNUF (SNA Upline Facility).

Systems Manager at Paul Munroe Hydraulics

January 1987 - January 1988 (1 year 1 month)

High-visibility, hands-on position. Responsible for maintaining HP3000 computer with 120 users and a wide-area network. Programmed in PowerHouse (Quiz, QTP, etc.) Extensive analysis and design with emphasis on directly coordinating with end-users to determine business requirements.

Consultant Programmer Analyst at Self employed

January 1985 - January 1987 (2 years 1 month)

Developed, debugged and maintained interactive and batch applications written in C, xBase, Lotus 1-2-3, COBOL and RPGII; supported and trained end users. Computers used: IBM PC, IBM System 36, and IBM System 34

Programmer Analyst at Leadtec Systems Inc

January 1983 - January 1985 (2 years 1 month)

Application was an interactive piecework payroll system for the apparel industry written in COBOL. Computers used: IBM System 36, IBM PC

Programmer Analyst at Germain's Inc

January 1981 - January 1983 (2 years 1 month)

Developed, debugged and maintained interactive and batch applications written in RPGII; supported and trained end users. Computer used: IBM System 34

Programmer Analyst at Shirley Software Systems

January 1979 - January 1981 (2 years 1 month)

Developed, debugged and maintained batch FORTRAN programs to handle PERT/CPM scheduling. Computers used: HP 3000, Prime and DEC.

Skills & Expertise

MySQL

ASP

UML

JavaScript

VBScript

Microsoft SQL Server

XHTML

jQuery

PHP

XML

JSP

Unix Shell Scripting

SQL

Visual Basic

Oracle

Oracle SQL Developer

SDL Tridion

HTML 5/4/3

CSS 2/1

ECMAScript

XML Schema

XPath

VBA

Ksh

Bash

Eclipse

Stored Procedures

JSDoc

JSUnit

XML DTD

Java

Oracle SQL

MS-SQL

Windows Scripting

HTA SQL Stored Procedures Web Development SDLC

Education

O'Reilly OSCON 2016

MEAN Architecture, 2016 - 2016

Union Bank In-House Training

Computer Associates (CA) SiteMinder Product Training, 2014

Union Bank In-House Training

SDL Tridion CMS Product Training, 2008

Union Bank In-House Training

2004

IBM Education Center

None, 1999 - 2000

InfoTec

Lotus Notes, 1997 - 1998

Data-Tech

1997

Control Data Institute

Computer Programming and Operations, 1978

Languages

English

(Full professional proficiency)

Geek

(Full professional proficiency)

Volunteer Experience

Toastmasters 1990-1993 at Union Bank

July 1990 - January 1993

Robert Raftery

Experienced Software Developer

braftery@protonmail.com



Contact Robert on LinkedIn